Koushik Katta Devops

Hyderabad, Telangana - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Koushik-Katta/a6b19244854199ec

DevOps Administrator with an experience of 3.4 years working in a challenging agile environment, looking forward for a position where I can use my knowledge pursuing my domain interests. I'm more aligned to work for companies where knowledge and intellectual ability takes the lead which can utilize a performance driven individual efficiently.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Devops Engineer

Infosys limited - Hyderabad, Telangana -

December 2014 to Present

Hyderabad, since December 2014 to till date.

Skill and Abilities:

Atlassian Tools: Jira, Confluence Configuration Management: Ansible /Chef

CI Tools: Jenkins

Monitoring Tools: Nagios

Cloud: AWS

Containerization: Docker Build Tools: Bamboo\Maven

Log Tools: Splunk

Databases: RDBMS, MYSQL, Oracle Database Programming Languages: Python and Java

Scripting: Power Shell

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux family, Redhat Linux

Middleware: Websphere, Tomcat, Websphere MQ

Responsibilities: DEVOPS ADMINISTRATOR

INFOSYS LTD.

Atlassian tools Release Management according

Infosys limited -

December 2014 to Present

to project needs.

- \checkmark Review and upgrade of Plugins to meet project requirements and to achieve better
- ✓ Configuring Automated Mail handlers, Webhooks as POC to test the new demands raised by

https://www.indeed.com/r/Koushik-Katta/a6b19244854199ec?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

- ✓ JIRA Project Management/Administration.
- ✓ Confluence Space Management/Administration.
- ✓ Bitbucket Project/Repository Management/Administration (Enterprise/DataCenter)
- ✓ Integration of Webhooks in Bitbucket.
- \checkmark Streamlining tools access management with Crowd.
- 2. Administration and Maintenance of Jenkins
- \checkmark Configure and maintain Jenkins slaves as per the requirement.
- ✓ Jenkins release management.
- \checkmark Work closely with Development teams to configure CI/CD Pipelines to automate their build & deployment process.
- ✓ Review, Installation/Upgrade and configuration of Jenkins Plugins.
- \checkmark Configuring proxy on the environments to enable security
- ✓ Debug build issues
- 3. Administration and Maintenance of Docker registry
- 4. Working with Open-Source Nagios plugins on demand basis to setup ICINGA monitoring for our on-premise Servers/Applications.
- 5. Alerting Setup Splunk.
- 6. Monitoring Dashboards setup using kibana.
- 7. Working with product support teams to resolve the product bugs.
- 8. Involve in client meetings and tool performance reviews to ensure stakeholder satisfaction.
- 9. Work closely with Infrastructure Teams to setup/maintain/improve the above mentioned application on large scale.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering

Lovely Professional University

2010 to 2014

Secondary School Certificate in education

Board of Intermediate education - Hyderabad, Telangana

2008 to 2010

Sister Nivedita School - Karimnagar, Telangana

2008

SKILLS

Jira, Ansible, Jenkins, Splunk, Nagios, Docker, Python, AWS, Bamboo, Linux, Git, Chef, Windows, Powershell Scripting

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- · Ability to learn new technologies and processes rapidly and implement them in the project.
- Highly motivated with very good problem solving and analytical skills Well organized, with excellent in multitasking and prioritizing the work.
- Effective communicator with an ability to convey ideas in speaking and writing.
- Excellent analytical and decision making skills.
- \bullet Ability to work in pressurized situation.
- Hard worker and goal oriented.
- Always ready to learn new skills